Guide to the Department of Athletics, Yale University, Records Documenting Tennis
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Athletics, Yale University, records documenting tennis
1909-2004
RU 942
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
12.25
(8 boxes)
The records consist of scrapbooks, correspondence, memos, and reports documenting tennis at Yale.
Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 38-B (YRG 38-B), Records documenting specific sports at Yale.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The records were transferred from the Department of Athletics, 2005; gift of the Connecticut Historical Society, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the materials is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of scrapbooks, correspondence, memos, and reports documenting tennis at Yale.
College sports; Tennis; Scrapbooks; Yale University Athletic Association; Yale University -- Sports; Yale University -- Tennis; Yale University. Dept. of Athletics
- Scrapbooks of the tennis team, 1918-1976; Accession 2006-A-037
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Scrapbooks
    - 1918-1921 (Box 6, Reel 1U)
      Scrapbooks for the years 1918-1975 are available on microfilm. Patrons must use HM FILM 178 instead of the original scrapbooks.
    - 1923-1924 (Box 1, Reel 1U)
    - 1926 (Box 2, Reel 2U)
    - 1948-1954 (Box 3, Reel 2U)
    - 1955-1969 (Box 4, Reel 2U)
    - 1969-1975 (Box 2)
    - 1976 [not microfilmed] (Box 5)
- Records of the tennis team, 1938-2004; Accession 2006-A-103
  Restricted until January 1, 2039
  - Men's Tennis
    - General, 1977-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 11)
    - Post Season, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 14)
    - Budget/Expenses, 1979-1986 (Box 1, Folder 15 - 16)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 17 - 18)
    - Z [ECAC and NCAA], 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Memorandums, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence [Steve Griggs], 1986 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence [Alex Dorato], 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Strength Programs, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Player Reports, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Recess, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Sport Organizations [Eastern Intercollegiate Tennis Association], 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Z, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Awards, 2003-2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Statistics, 1949-1950 (Box 1, Folder 29A)
  - Women's Tennis
    - Post Season, 1978-1988 (Box 1, Folder 30 - 32)
    - General, 1979-1991 (Box 1, Folder 33 - 40)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 41 - 43)
    - Budget, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Z, 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 45 - 46)
    - Japan, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Junior Varsity, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Recess, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - New England Lawn Tennis Association, 1938, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Eastern Intercollegiate Tennis Association (EITA), 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Yale Tennis Association
    - General, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Newsletters, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Tennis Classic, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Yale Women's Tennis Association
    - General, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Soviet Union Trip, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - William Hinchcliff Endowment, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Men's Tennis Publications, 1971-1998 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Women's Tennis Publications, 1978-1997 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Practice schedule, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Scrapbook of the Yale Tennis Association, 1909-1911; Accession 2013-A-042 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  This accession consists of a scrapbook documenting activities of the Yale University Tennis Association and includes newspaper clippings and event programs.